

Emilio
Ziniades
ECONOMICS GRADUATE



Address

Bo-Kaap Cape Town 8001

Phone Number +(27) 83 388 4366

Email Address emilioziniades@gmail.com

LinkedIn Emilio Ziniades

OVERVIEW

I am a South African born in
Johannesburg and living in Cape
Town. After studying economics for
four years at the University of Cape
Town, I have developed a great
interest in the discipline, and
particularly in the state of the South
African economy.

My academic interests are the intersecting crises of debt, unemployment, inequality and poverty, as well as the growing challenge of climate change. In addition, I am interested in the progress of African Intergration, particularly the African Continental Free Trade Area, and this was the topic of my honours dissertation paper. I believe there is an important role for state policy guided by sound economic analysis, which can improve the lot of its citizens.

CERTIFICATIONS

Complete Python Bootcamp: From zero to hero in Python Udemy

June 2020

Certificate available upon request. **Link to course**

SKILLS

Python Intermediate R & RStudio Beginner

Stata Intermediat Word, Excel and Powerpoint

Adobe Illustrator

Competent Wordpress

Beginner webs develope host

website
development &
hosting
Proficient

LANGUAGES

English Afrikaans
Native Basic

French Greek
Basic Basic

HOBBIES

Reading books, watching films

Writing

Five-a-side soccer, running and yoga

Cooking and baking

WORK EXPERIENCE

Emilio Tech

Owner

(December 2020 - Present)

Freelance technical consulting business, providing support for a variety of jobs including cryptocurrency technology consulting and website development.

Monkey Films

Office Manager and Production Assistant

(January 2020 - April 2020)

Addressed various technical and administrative issues arising on film set and in the office, as well as assisting production both during shooting and in preproduction.

Phaphama SEDI (Social Enterprise Development

Initiative)

(February 2019 - November 2019)

Consultant

Consulted to All-in-One Online Shop, a small business based in Philippi which delivers groceries in Zimbabwe. Provided support regarding financial record-keeping, overall business strategy, online brand image and maintenance of customer relations.

University of Cape Town

Teaching Assistant

(January 2018 - December 2019)

Taught and marked essays for a variety of undergraduate Philosophy and Economics courses (PHI1024F, PHI2037F, ECO2004S and ECO3025S). Responsibilities included teaching weekly classes as well as essay, test and exam marking.

Emilio Tutors

Owner

(January 2016 - Present)

One-person tutoring business. 1-on-1 and group tutoring lessons conducted for high school students in Maths, History and Science, and for undergraduate university students in Economics. In addition to teaching, I am responsible for all financial, administrative and IT-related roles.

EDUCATION

University of Cape Town

(January 2019 - December 2019)

Bachelor of Commerce Honours in Economics

Degree GPA: 74.5%

Degree obtained in the second-class division one. Class medal obtained for Environmental Economics (ECO40525).

University of Cape Town

(January 2016 -December 2018)

Bachelor of Social Sciences in Politics, Philosophy and Economics

Degree GPA: 79%

Degree obtained with distinction, and a distinction received in Economics. Placed on the Humanities Dean's List in all three years of study. Awarded 3 class medals for Introduction to Philosophy (PHI1024F), Introduction to Politics (POL1004F) and, Cooperation and Competition (ECO2007S).

St John's College

(January 2011 - December 2015)

IEB Matric Certificate

Matric GPA: 91%

Matric obtained with 9 distinction. Top-acheiving student (highest overall average) for the class of 2015. Placed in the top 1 percent of IEB candidates for Maths, English, Science, History and Advanced Programme Maths.

AWARDS

Second Prefect

St John's College

October 2014

Deputy head-boy in matric year. Attended meetings with senior staff members. Co-ordinated a soup kitchen. Presented a student survey of the dining hall to the boarding committee.

Humanities Faculty Entrance Scholarship

University of Cape Town

January 2016

Partial scholarship for academic fees.

3 x Humanities Dean's List (2016, 2017, 2018)

University of Cape Town

Award for academic excellence. Only awarded to top 20% of each faculty.

Golden Key Society Member (2016-2019)

Golden Key Society

Consistently maintained GK membership across four consecutive years of study. Membership awarded to top 15 percent of each faculty every year.

REFERENCES

anthony.black@uct.ac.za

Anthony Black	Anne Nettleton	Clare van Zyl
Professor, School of	Deputy Headmistress, St	Executive Producer,
Economics, University of	John's College	Monkey Films
Cape Town	+447341878206	+27828554314
021 650 2729	nettlet on anne@gmail.comclare@monkey films.co.za	